HEND IBRAHIM MOHAMED

+2) 01551304568 | Nasr City, Cairo | hendibrahim468@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/hendibrahimseo/

CAREER OBJECTIVE:

Experience over 2 years in several industries such as (real estate, Interior design, Digital Marketing, Feasibility study, English Learning, Mom and Baby care, Medicine, Beauty, Fashion, Forex, Cars, service companies, and Eecommerce websites) and professional experience in content writing, digital marketing, Link building, Project Management, SEO keyword Research, SEO strategy performance, Increased traffic and rankings, and achieve maximum ROI in paid search campaigns, and excellent user in Google Systems. WordPress, Yoast, and Rank Math. Seeking an SEO Specialist position to apply my experiences in freelance work, project management, and SEO to raise the level of your platform.

KEY SKILLS:

- Critical Thinking
- Content Creation
- Keyword research
- Google Adwords
- Link building
- Project Management
- Task management:
- Risk management:
- Self-Learning
- HTML & CSS
- Flexibility
- Research
- Analytics
- On-page SEO
- Customer Services
- Content Marketing
- **Digital Marketing**
- Social Media
 - Content management system (CMS)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

Iff Store. Saudi Arabia.

(May2022-Present)

SEO Specialist, YouTube SEO Specialist (Full-Time)

- Drive targeted and loyal traffic to a website by community building.
- Integrate content marketing strategies.
- Monitor the algorithms set by the search engines to keep up to date with changes.

Nasphones. (Apr2022-Present)

SEO Specialist (Freelance)

- Update content and website links for maximum optimization and search engine rankings.
- Review and analyze client sites for areas that be improved and optimized.
- Execute tests, collect and analyze data and results, and identify trends and insights to achieve maximum ROI in paid search campaigns.

Asehaonline. (May2022-Jun2022)

SEO Specialist (Freelance)

- Solved technical problems on the site with the creation of an effective content strategy, which led to the daily clicks on the site reaching 2600 instead of 1400 clicks.
- Monitored daily performance metrics to understand SEO strategy performance.
- Wrote compelling and high-quality website content, including blog posts and page descriptions
- Updated content and website links for maximum optimization and search engine rankings

MatsMall, United Arab Emirates.

(Apr2021-Mar2022)

SEO Specialist (Part-time)

- Added the right keywords for business in (Google, Bing, and Yandex) to increase organic traffic on the site and ranked the most important keyword for the business in Google
- Researched for SEO keywords to use throughout the company's website and marketing materials.
- Created effective SEO content for blogs, websites, and social media accounts.
- Monitored daily performance metrics to understand SEO strategy performance.
- Improved rankings from page 5 to Top 5 for 10+ high-competition keywords in the interior design niche.

ENCAFE Conversation program, Egypt.

(Sep2021-Oct2021)

YouTube Specialist (Freelance)

- Increased watch time by 43.5 % more than usual, impression by 11%, click-through rate by 44%, and Number of Subscribers by 96%.
- Managed partner's channel (videos upload, content management, and SEO optimization).
- Optimized the videos properly as per YouTube guidelines.
- Met the short, medium, and long-term plans discussed with the founder.
- Suggested new ideas for our YouTube content.

Reiyada, Saudi Arabia.

(Sep2021-Oct2021)

SEO Specialist (Part-Time)

- Managed all SEO activities and content creation.
- Increased Website Traffic & Ranking in Google & All Search Engines.
- Optimized copy and landing pages for search engine marketing
- Examined Competitor's analysis using Ahrefs & SEMrush to find competing domains

E5dmny, Saudi Arabia.

(May2021-Sep2021)

SEO Specialist & YouTube SEO specialist (Part-Time)

- Made the site appear in the top 3 results on Google in Saudi Arabia.
- Developed and implemented effective search engine optimization (SEO) strategies, techniques, and tactics to increase the number
 of visitors to the website and obtain a high-ranking placement on the Google results page, and generate more leads for the business.
- Updated white hat and black hat SEO strategies have been to avoid adhering to search engine guidelines.
- Analyzed keywords and SEO techniques used by competitors
- Identified powerful keywords to drive the most valuable traffic.

Agarmap, Egypt. (Feb2021-Jun2021)

On-page SEO specialist (Full-Time)

- Achieved a successful on-page SEO for many articles in the field of real estate.
- Established the headings H1, H2, H3, H4, H5, and H6.
- Created the optimum meta titles, optimum meta descriptions, and friendly URL.
- Ensured that all articles fit SEO rules.
- Used Screaming Frog to perform technical SEO audits.

Hayah core. (Nov2020-Apr2021)

SEO Specialist, (Freelance)

- Created a content strategy that has increased site traffic from zero to 12k clicks per month.
- Researched and analyzed competitor SEO activities.
- Performed ongoing keyword research: which includes discovering and expansion of keyword opportunities.

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT:

- Search Engine Optimization Course, HubSpot Academy. (Mar2022)
- YouTube Masterclass Your Complete Guide to YouTube, Udemy. (Sep2021)
- Google Analytics Essential Training, LinkedIn.
 (Feb2021)
- Improve SEO for Your Website, LinkedIn. (Feb2021)

•	Learning Data Analytics, LinkedIn.	(Feb2021)
•	Local SEO, LinkedIn.	(Feb2021)
•	Marketing Tools: SEO, LinkedIn.	(Feb2021)
•	Online Marketing Foundations, LinkedIn.	(Feb2021)
•	SEO: Ecommerce Strategies, LinkedIn.	(Feb2021)
•	WordPress Ecommerce: Easy Digital Downloads, LinkedIn.	(Feb2021)
•	WordPress: Customizing WooCommerce Themes, LinkedIn.	(Feb2021)
•	Advanced Google Analytics, Google Analytics for Business.	(Jan2021)
•	Google Analytics for Power Users, Google Analytics for Business.	(Jan2021)
•	Advanced SEO: Search Factors, LinkedIn.	(Jan2021)
•	Google Analytics: Spam Proofing, LinkedIn.	(Jan2021)
•	Improve SEO for Your Ecommerce Site, LinkedIn.	(Jan2021)
•	Learning Google Tag Manager (2018), Linkedln.	(Jan2021)
•	SEO: Keyword Strategy, LinkedIn.	(Jan2021)
•	Writing a Compelling Blog Post, LinkedIn.	(Jan2021)
•	Digital marketing challenger Track, Udacity.	(Oct2020)
•	Marketing Plan, Udemy.	(Oct2020)
•	Marketing content step by step workshop, Udemy.	(Oct2020)
•	Digital Marketing, Mahart mn Google, Google.	(Sep2020)
•	Google Analytics for Beginners, Google Analytics for Business.	(Jan2021)

EDUCATION:

Al-Azhar university, Al-Azhar.

(Sep2017-Present)

Faculty of medicine.

Udacity. (Sep2020-Sep2021)

Digital marketing Diploma.

SKILLS:

Language skills:

Arabic: Mother Tongue
 English: Fluent

Technical skills:

- Professional user of Microsoft Office (Word, Power point, and Excel)
- Google Systems (Google Sheets, Tag Manager, and Google Analytics)
- Writing Systems (WordPress, SEO, Yoast, and Rank Math)

PERSONAL INFORMATION:

• Date of Birth: 26, Dec, 1999.